Eikaiwa Time Trial
Let's get started with Day 11 for the month of September.
Hi everyone! I'm Steve Sarese.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
Let's check out a new week of Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Hello, everyone. It's Nora here.
Are you enjoying Scotland?
On Friday, we get dressed up for a special occasion.
It's a nice afternoon tea at a Scottish castle.
See you then.
Thanks, Nora.
Everyone is dressed up nicely for an afternoon tea.
In Scotland.
先週の対話カラオケでレンタルしたキルトを着て、アフターヌーンティーに参加しますよ。
そんな場面での会話に向けて、今週も服にまつわる英語表現を身につけていきましょう。
今回のキーワードはこちら。
Outfit
このアウトフィットはどんな場面で使うのか、練習を通して身につけていきましょう。
早速トレーニングを始めましょう。
Alright, it's time for your first try.
S.P.R. Training
I wore a Scottish outfit.
I wore Scottish clothes,よりも、全体の服のコーディネートについて言うなら、アウトフィット。
では、アウトフィットを使ってこちらも言ってみよう。
そのスコットランドの服は似合っていますね。
That Scottish outfit から言ってください。
どうぞ。
どこでその服を買ったのですか؟
実はこの服はレンタルです 特別な機会にキルトを着る人もいます
テレビで一度キルトを見たことがあります I've seen から言ってください
どうぞ
思ったより重いです
It's heavier
から言ってください
どうぞ
では次の文に行く前に
この語彙を確認しましょう
地元の人たち
How do you say that in English?
The answer is, the locals.
Local peopleよりも、the localsはよく使います。
では、the localsを使ってこの文を言ってみよう。
地元の人たちに溶け込みたかったんです。
きっとスコットランドの地元の人たちに溶け込めますよ。
この服だと浮きますか?
OK, how was your first round?
Did you try to say each one?
一回目の挑戦はいかがでしたか?
ではここで回答例をチェックしましょう。
そして今週は少しレベルアップして英語での解説も混ぜてみます。
So now, you can check your answers with mine.
Okay, listen closely.
スコットランドの服を着ました。
I wore a Scottish outfit.
そのスコットランドの服は似合っていますね。
That Scottish outfit looks good on you.
どこでその服を買ったのですか?
Where did you get that outfit?
実はこの服はレンタルです。
Actually, I'm renting this outfit.
This outfit is a rental.
でも通じますが、回答例のように、
現在進行形でI'm renting this outfitの方が分かりやすくおすすめです。
特別な機会にキルトを着る人もいます。
Some people wear kilts for special occasions.
テレビで一度キルトを見たことがあります。
I've seen a kilt on TV once.
思ったより重いです。
It's heavier than I expected.
You can also say it's heavier than I thought,
but in most cases,
思ったより〜 is usually
比較級 plus than I expected.
Alright, here's the next one.
地元の人たちに溶け込みたかったんです
I wanted to fit in with the locals
溶け込む
You can use the phrase fit in or blend in
I wanted to fit in, blend in with the locals
Here's the next one
きっとスコットランドの地元の人たちに溶け込めますよ
You'll fit in with the locals in Scotland
この服だと浮きますか?
Does this outfit stand out too much?
浮くを簡単な英語で言えます
Stand out
目立つ
Does this outfit stand out too much?
OK
Did you understand today's phrases?
Alright
Now it's your turn to try them one more time
This is your chance to do a little better than before
OK, let's go
スコットランドの服を着ました どうぞ
I wore a Scottish outfit
そのスコットランドの服は似合っていますね
That Scottish outfit looks good on you
どこでその服を買ったのですか
Where did you get that outfit?
Jitsu wa kono fuku wa rentaru desu.
Actually, I'm renting this outfit.
Tokubetsu na kikai ni kiltou kiru hito mo imasu.
Some people wear kilts for special occasions.
テレビで一度キルトを見たことがあります
I've seen a kilt on TV once
思ったより重いです
It's heavier than I expected
地元の人たちに溶け込みたかったんです
I wanted to fit in with the locals.
きっとスコットランドの地元の人たちにとけこめますよ。
You'll fit in with the locals in Scotland.
この服だと浮きますか?
Does this outfit stand out too much?
Okay, time's up.
Well, how did you do?
So, everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Ekiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.